Guide to the Amos Burg Photographs 1889-1986
Oregon Historical Society, Research Library
- Amos Burg, His Family, and His Adventures, 1889-1950; Subgroup 1
  - Adventurer/Lecturer/Writer, 1920-1950; Series C
    - Scandinavian trip for Encyclopaedia Britannica Films, 1949; Subseries 35; 267 photographs
      - Hardanger Fjord, Norway, 1949 (Box-folder 14/18)
      - Jaeren, Norway, 1949 (Box-folder 14/19)
      - Latefoss Waterfall, Norway, 1949 (Box-folder 14/20)
      - Odda, Norway, 1949 (Box-folder 14/21)
      - Lofthus, Norway, 1949 (Box-folder 14/22)
      - Sörfjord (near Hardnager Fjord), Norway, 1949 (Box-folder 14/23)
      - Bergen, Norway, 1949 (Box-folder 14/24)
      - Bergen, Norway--harbor, 1949 (Box-folder 14/25)
      - Bergen, Norway--fish market, 1949 (Box-folder 14/26)
      - Bergen, Norway--homes, 1949 (Box-folder 14/27)
      - Fantoft Stave Church near Bergen, Norway, 1949 (Box-folder 14/28)
      - Troldhaugun, Edvard Grieg's home near Bergen, Norway, 1949 (Box-folder 14/29)
      - Bergen, Norway--vicinity, 1949 (Box-folder 14/30)
      - Ålesund, Norway, 1949 (Box-folder 14/31)
      - Western Norway, 1949 (Box-folder 14/32)
      - North Trøndelag, Norway, 1949 (Box-folder 14/33)
      - Helgeland, Norway, 1949 (Box-folder 14/34)
      - Bodø, Norway, 1949 (Box-folder 14/35)
      - Lofoten Islands, Norway, 1949 (Box-folder 14/36)
      - Vesterålen Islands, Norway, 1949 (Box-folder 14/37)
      - Tromsö, Norway, 1949 (Box-folder 14/38)
      - Hammerfestg, Norway, 1949 (Box-folder 14/39)
      - Havøy Island, Norway, 1949 (Box-folder 14/40)
      - Havøysund, Norway, 1949 (Box-folder 14/41)
      - Honningsvåg, Norway, 1949 (Box-folder 14/42)
      - Båtsford, Norway, 1949 (Box-folder 14/43)
      - Vardö, Norway, 1949 (Box-folder 14/44)
      - Vadsö, Norway, 1949 (Box-folder 14/45)
      - Kirkenes, 1949 (Box-folder 14/46)
      - Finnmark area, Norway--drying codfish, 1949 (Box-folder 14/47)
      - Finnmark area, Norway--fishing fleets, 1949 (Box-folder 14/48)
      - Norwegian fjord horse, 1949 (Box-folder 14/49)
      - Norway--unidentified people, 1949 (Box-folder 14/50)
      - Denmark--dairy products, 1949 (Box-folder 14/51)
    - North Star trip for National Geographic, 1950; Subseries 36; 1,039 photographs (Box 15-18)
      Amos Burg sailed on the SS Alaska to Sitka, where he boarded the MV North Star for a voyage through the Bering Sea and the Arctic Ocean to Point Barrow and back. Burg filmed many Eskimo villages, as the ship dropped supples at 45 villages along the route. He produced a lecture film and an article for National Geographic, "North Star Sails Alaska's Wild West" (July 1952, pp. 57-86).
      The prints are arranged numerically in order of Burg's numbers in all of Boxes 15-17 and Folders 1-8 in Box 18.
    - Photographs from other sources, 1903-circa 1950; Subseries 37; 1,039 photographs.
      Although Burg made the bulk of the images in this collection, he also obtained images by other photographers for reference and use in his projects.
      The images are arranged into two sub-subseries: North America (including Hawaii) and Elsewhere in the World. Within the sub-subseries, images are arranged alphabetically by location.
      - North America (including Hawaii), 1903-circa 1950
        - Alaska, circa 1920-circa 1950 (Box-folder 18/8)
        - Alaska--published by Lomen Brothers (Nome), 1903; 1906 (Box-folder 18/9)
        - Alaska--aerials by U.S. Forest Service, 1929 (Box-folder 18/10)
        - Alaska--Bristol Bay fisheries, circa 1935 (Box-folder 18/11)
        - Alaska--Hasselberg, Al, 1910-circa 1920 (Box-folder 18/12)
        - Alaska--ships, circa 1930 (Box-folder 18/13)
        - British Columbia, circa 1930-circa 1950 (Box-folder 18/14)
        - Hawaii, 1928 (Box-folder 18/15)
        - Idaho, 1931 (Box-folder 18/16)
        - Northwest Territories, circa 1925 (Box-folder 18/17)
        - Northwest Territories--by O.S. Finnie, 1929 (Box-folder 18/18)
        - Texas, circa 1940 (Box-folder 18/19)
        - Washington state, circa 1930 (Box-folder 18/20)
        - Wyoming, circa 1930 (Box-folder 18/21)
        - Yukon Territory, 1898 (Box-folder 18/22)
      - Elsewhere in the World, 1933-circa 1935
        - Barbados--by Ardia Taylor, 1934 (Box-folder 18/23)
        - New Guinea, 1933 (Box-folder 18/24)
        - South America, circa 1935 (Box-folder 18/25)